Christopher Evelyn James

Belfast, Northern Ireland, United Kingdom



https://cjamesni.github.io

Summary

Professional summary:

IT Systems engineer with 5+ years of experience in working with enterprise IT infrastructure and services. Specialises in IT system engineering, deployment, administration and automation. Special interests include: unix, linux & macOS internals, network routing & switching and automation software.

Key skills & experience:

- System administration of Unix and Linux environments supporting: *nix operating systems, Bash and Python.
- System administration and engineering of Apple desktop hardware and software applications for enterprise including: macOS, Xcode, Instruments, Bash, Python, Swift and Jamf Pro.
- Network administration and network monitoring for enterprise including; a strong working knowledge of common network infrastructure and network protocol (CCNA, N+ and Splunk certified).
- Endpoint system security management including: CVE review, vulnerability remediation, OS hardening, user access & application control.
- Co-leading management of a global staff device collection and co-ordinating global operating system deployment projects.
- Client application packaging and scripting for macOS & iOS. Client application code-signing and enterprise distribution for macOS & iOS.
- Web application support and development including: customisation, configuration and deployment of a modern enterprise web service (VPC hosted with SSO and 2FA access) with supporting open source API connection components written in Python, deploying solution components to QA & Production enterprise environments.
- Version control using Git, GitHub and Bitbucket: https://cjamesni.github.io (My personal GitHub site)
- System engineering experience working with AWS hosted solutions supporting: AWS CLI, NGINX+, EC2 and RDS.

Experience



Desktop Engineer III, Global Desktop & IT Infrastructure Services

CME Group

Dec 2017 - Present (2 years 4 months +)

- Primarily focused on delivering systems administration and systems engineering tasks for global desktop environments and IT infrastructure at CME Group.
- Specifically responsible for co-leading the management of a large staff device collection spanning the US, Europe and Asia, adopting a 'security first' approach.
- Standardising team processes and writing technical documentation.
- Research & development for individual and team projects.



Desktop Engineer II, Global Desktop & IT Infrastructure Services

CME Group

Mar 2016 - Dec 2017 (1 year 10 months)

- Endpoint System Solutions Group member delivering systems support and systems engineering functions at CME Group.
- Escalation point for members of the internal customer support group locally and globally.
- Collaborating with teams from the Infrastructure & Operations department to remediate incidents of network, system or application(s) downtime.

- Managing endpoint system security, including: CVE review, vulnerability remediation, OS hardening, user access and application control.
- Co-ordinating global OS deployment projects, including: Jira based issue and task tracking, creation and maintenance of Epics, Stories, Dashboards and Sprints.
- Preparing macOS application packages, scripts, security and system updates for global distribution.
- Managing and assigning site assets.

COBALT. Infrastructure Engineer II, Managed IT Services, Europe & CIS

Cobalt Technology

Jan 2015 - Mar 2016 (1 year 3 months)

- Disaster recovery operations including monitoring the back-up and replication of virtual machines from customer-owned production environments to a managed secondary site (using VMware vSphere 5.5 and Veeam B&R 7). Managing snapshots and restarting failed replication jobs.
- Escalating significant back-up and replication issues to senior infrastructure engineers.
- Updating back-levelled firmware on IBM storage systems and collecting DSA system logs for vendor diagnostics as required.
- Systems administration for hybrid Microsoft environments using PowerShell and Windows server administration tools.
- Managing client Active Directory forests including OU, security group, user and computer objects.
- -Managing client GPOs via Group Policy Management Editor.
- Lync server administration of online and enterprise voice users. Assigning telephone DDIs.
- Implementing Lync server QoS to improve communication quality.
- Exchange server administration. Managing user mailbox assignment, distribution groups and global address lists. Setting up Unified Exchange Messaging services.
- Managing SharePoint site collections. Provisioning site storage and structuring SharePoint sites including subsites, libraries, lists and applications.
- Troubleshooting and reporting on managed IT services for customers. Liaising with third parties to resolve problems.
- Supporting client's LAN networks.



Technical Support Advisor, Samsung Electronics, UK Customer Services

Teleperformance

Sep 2012 - Dec 2014 (2 years 4 months)

- Two years plus contact centre experience with the Teleperformance Group working as a technical support advisor for their client company, Samsung Electronics UK.
- Responsible for administering technical services and troubleshooting support for consumers of Samsung multimedia electronics products across the UK.
- Managing system configurations, hardware diagnostics, software updates and system recoveries.
- Explaining technical instructions to consumers via telephone, email and social media.

Laboratory Technician, Norbrook Laboratories Ltd, UK

Norbrook Laboratories Itd

Apr 2009 - Sep 2009 (6 months)

- Six months work experience as a Lab Technician based within Norbrook Laboratories Microbiology Department.
- I was responsible for reading and recording test data onto company paperwork, creating batch reports and updating company databases.

Education



Top-up Bachelor of Science (Honours), Computing and Information Technology

Currently enrolled with a number of modules pending.

Modules: Software engineering - Web, mobile and cloud technologies - Data management and analysis - IT Project

Ulster University

Foundation (CertHE), Information and Communication Technology

Modules:

Systems Analysis - Networks & Communications - Programming I - Computer Technologies - Data Driven Web Authoring - Introduction to Databases

Licenses & Certifications

Cloud Computing Applications, Part 1: Cloud Systems and Infrastructure by University of Illinois UC - Coursera Course Certificates

JZ7PVOCVUZ2G

Jamf CCT: Certified Casper Technician - Jamf

CAD510: VMware Certified Associate in Data Center Virtualization - VMware

Issued Mar 2015 - Expires Mar 2017 15811506-A547-E8A8D8E0E7A6

N10-006: CompTIA Network+ CE - CompTIA

Issued Oct 2015 - Expires Oct 2018 289267117-47687342

≡XIN ITIL® V3 Foundation Certification in IT Service Management - EXIN

5406360.20418524

Jamf CCA: Certified Casper Administrator - Jamf

Cloud Computing Applications, Part 2: Big Data and Applications in the Cloud by University of Illinois UC - Coursera Course Certificates

J2AHP62LR3YM

Splunk Certified User - Splunk

Cert-192053

200-125 CCNA: Routing and Switching - Cisco

Issued Feb 2020 - Expires Feb 2023 2X4GL4XJ9PFQ15GK

200-301 CCNA: Implementing and Administering Cisco Solutions - Cisco

Issued Feb 2020 - Expires Feb 2023 F3SKBLDD8DF4Q2WP

Honors & Awards

CME Group Excellence Award, October 2016 - Ryan Eavy, Dir Technology Architecture Awarded in recognition of contribution to the research and development of emerging technology at CME Group.

CME Group Excellence Award, July 2017 - Peter Metzke, Dir Systems Engineering

Awarded in recognition of delivering several high profile items and services on behalf of Desktop Systems Engineering at CME Group.

CME Group Excellence Award, August 2017 - Peter Campbell, Business Operations Awarded in recognition of a great ability, approach and professional demeanour in delivering ESSG services under pressure at CME Group.

Skills

Bash • Network Engineering • Systems Engineering • Troubleshooting • System Administration • Network Administration • Virtualization • System Deployment • Shell Scripting • Internet Protocol Suite (TCP/IP)